in the markets to make money you have to
learn how to speak the language you have
to understand the signals that it's
giving you whether it's going to go up
or whether it's going to go down and
this for most of us that are experienced
in the market it's actually very easy
you just simply read the language and
it's pretty much obvious what the market
is telling you what it's going to do and
trust me when I tell you this when you
learn how to read the language that the
market is showing you you turn into a
money magnet and personally price action
is the best way to read this language
that the market gives you it's what I've
been using for about 6 years and it's
given me results like these or even
results like these price action tells
you the intentions of whether price is
going to have a strong move up or
whether it's going to have a strong move
down or even not have any move at all
and it's very simple to understand even
when it's having a retracement into an
area of interest and having a reaction
or just using it to retest now this is
going to make sense if this is your
first time hearing what price action is
in the details that I'm going to explain
in this video and it's actually very
simple to tell you can literally see
when prices have having a retracement to
a Zone and it's going to reject from it
or not reject at all it's what price
action shows you so let's see in this
video what price action is and how you
can take advantage from the signals that
it gives you so you can use it on a
day-to-day basis while you're reading
the markets and I'm also going to add
some examples on trades that I've
personally taken myself simply using
price action to show you how effective
it can be and you can use it right away
so to add we already know that price
action is the language that the market
shows you to make its intentions clear
through these candlesticks or these
lines that you see on a computer screen
now keep in mind that every single
language has a way of expressing itself
same way how us humans we have different
languages we have English Spanish
Japanese French Italian all these
different type of languages same as how
the market has different languages to
show us what it's trying to tell us and
in the markets that I've been trading
for 6 years and pretty much 90% of the
rest of the Traders are called Japanese
candlesticks this is the type of
language that we are reading from the
charts and these candlesticks they
contain Ain a lot of information and by
reading them the right way with price
action you're able to anticipate what's
going to happen next so let's actually
get into a little bit more detail on
what the price action is with these
Japanese candlesticks so to start off
Japanese candlesticks which is price
action consist of these candlesticks the
candlesticks that they have a high point
a low Point open price close price what
everybody already knows but they consist
of strong candlesticks or weaker
candlesticks this chart that you see
right here you can see not every single
cand stick is the same every single
Candlestick is different in size
different size body different size Wick
so it consists of a lot of different
variables that create the price action
chart that we read every single day to
make money in the markets so the
majority of the things you should be
looking for are for strong candlesticks
which would be a bullish engulfing
marabu candlesticks and you also want to
be looking for long tails or long Wicks
which these are the confirmations that
price is rejecting certain zones this
creates a price action confirming that
we are now going to head to the upside
or now going to head to the downside so
let's start off with strong candlesticks
what do they look like what they consist
of and it's what this is right here
which is a marabu Candlestick so this is
a Candlestick that closes with no Wick
at the top and no Wick at the bottom
pretty much from the moment price opened
it just shot up and then it closed there
continua the momentum of price this is
indicating to you that a lot of buyers
are coming into the market showing to
you that it's a strong indication to buy
so once you read this Candlestick along
with the price action of the market this
is a good indication to now buy
obviously if the Candlestick reverses
and it has a strong marabu Candlestick
to the downside this is a strong
confirmation that the market is now
going to sell a strong moreu Candlestick
it usually eats up the last one or two
candlesticks where it would also be a
bullish or bearish engulfing Candlestick
which is personally one of my favorite
confirmation signals next we have the
wix these Wicks sometimes people think
of them as spinning tops shooting stars
even a sword depending on how small the
bottom Wick is and how top the wick is
so these are confirmations in price
action that price is now rejecting
certain zones in price usually they
happen at a strong level of support or a
strong level of resistance which added
by this price action confirms to us that
we're are now going to reject it so the
longer the wick is the better because
this means that it has a stronger
rejection that means price went all the
way to that point and then the buyers in
the market completely raised price all
the way back up same thing if you have
it out of resistance and you have a
really big wick this means that price
went all the way up to the high and then
sellers came and drove price all the way
down so you want to look for multiple
Wicks and the bigger the wick the better
the confirmation because it means that
sellers are completely beating up buyers
in a resistance level and in a support
level the bigger the wick it is there as
well the bigger the wig that means that
the buyers are outdoing the sellers by
complete so you're probably wondering
what is too big and what is too small so
a big Candlestick is usually when it
eats up the last three or four
candlesticks that's considered a big
Candlestick because let's say you're on
the hourly time frame three candlesticks
just got completely engulfed by one
Candlestick that's a strong confirmation
that within that 1 hour it completely
outdated the work of 3 hours I
personally think any Candlestick that
eats the last three candles is a strong
Candlestick now this also happens to the
upside or this can also happen to the
downside and then a normal Candlestick
it's could range anywhere from 20 to
maybe 15 Pips obviously depending on the
momentum of the market depending in the
zone it realistically varies but what
you want to make sure is you just want
to compare it to the last candlesticks
if it's a little bit bigger a little bit
smaller you can kind of see it based off
of the way the market is but the main
focus should be the big candlesticks the
ones that stand out because that is your
entry confirmation that price is now
reversing or heading in the continuous
direction of where you're intended to
take the trade so now to add like a
little sprinkle on top which is
personally my favorite is Candlestick
patterns so Candlestick patterns happen
throughout the whole entire chart and
what this consists of is a series of
patterns that happen within the
candlesticks these are sequences that
happen with let's say two or three
candlesticks that equal to a pattern
these happen at key points and indicate
to us that price is going to go up or to
the downside and it is key to having
strong price action in your chart so
some examples of patterns we can start
off with reversal patterns so reversal
patterns are price action points that
show to us that price is literally going
to reverse it's pretty self-explanatory
one of my best examples can either be a
Evening Star formation or a head and
shoulders these are very simple patterns
that you see all the time in the charts
Evening Star formation consists of a
three pattern confirmation indicating to
you that price is then going to now
reverse and then the head and shoulders
is also a pattern that you pretty much
see on the lower time frames for the
majority of the time but it is more
respected on the higher time frame even
though you see it all of the time as
well it just takes a little bit longer
to play out and this as well once the
complete Head and Shoulders has played
out it is a beautiful reversal pattern
to indicate to you that the market has
then changed and now this can happen at
a level of support as well which you
would have then a Morning Star formation
which indicating to you that price is
now going to reverse and head to the
upside and then you also have a inverted
Head and Shoulders at a support level
indicating to you that price is then now
shifting from downwards Trend to now
upwards turn it's the beauty of price
action and then we also have
continuation patterns which is probably
the simplest out of the textbook which
is break and retest one of my favorites
that I use every single week that I
trade and it's probably the key to my
strategy and as as you if you use it the
right way trust me it's going to work
trust me break and retest literally
consists of break and retest let's say
you have a strong resistance level you
literally break it retest it confirm
that's it that's all you need you just
have to wait for the right confirmation
to happen in the market and key to that
is being extremely patient by making
sure that it's not a fake out which is
very key so now you know how to
interpret the Japanese candlesticks you
want to make sure that you know what
they're doing at all times even if
you're not taking a trade now it's time
to learn their language and by learning
the language this actually means that
you're not going to be looking at every
single Wick or every single Candlestick
as crazy as that might sound you should
only be looking at the markets when
something big is going to happen when
there's a high probability trade setup
and for these high probability trade
setups to happen you have to have a
strong area of Interest or a Zone where
you're looking to actually enter a trade
and it's not the same that you're going
to have a huge Wick that price just
leaves in the random of the chart
anywhere no you want to make sure these
Wicks or these rejections are happening
at a strong Zone that you're interested
in so now let's actually go to the Chart
so I can show you guys what I've been
just talking about so it's not just
Chinese right so this right in front of
us is price action this is where you're
actually going to be able to read what
the market is telling you this is the
language that the charts are giving you
and we're reading it and interpreting it
and making money with it so to start off
this is a beautiful price action
structure shift right here beautiful
breaking retest continuation and this is
a prime example of what a big
Candlestick would look like like this
right here is a bullish Candlestick as
you can see it's obviously heading to
the upside and as you can see it has
engulfed and it has eaten the last one
two three four candlesticks so this is
an indication to you like I mentioned
that this is a strong Candlestick a
strong bullish Candlestick is one that
has eaten the last three candlesticks
now after that huge Candlestick what do
then we have we then have a break and
then a retest of the last structure
point this is beautiful price action
because it's indicating to US market
continuation after that then we have our
Candlestick rejections these are the
Wicks that I was mentioning to you guys
these are the Wicks the bigger the wick
this means price went all the way down
here couldn't hold up and then it
completely rejected so now you have a
mix of a big bullish candlesticks along
with two rejection Wicks from a previous
structure point this is the price action
that you want to see to see Trend
continuation and then now you have your
morning star bullish and golfing
Candlestick this is key to now
continuation with your trade along with
break and retest and all of this
beautiful price action that you're
seeing fall right in front of you this
is actually a trade that I caught myself
and I think I made around anywhere from
$30 to $40,000 on this very trade that
you're looking at right here so now that
you know how to identify simple Market
moves with price action now let's
actually see the Candlestick formations
let's see how these patterns work and
it's very key that you understand this
because these are the most effective
patterns that the markets do every
single day and these are the ones that I
use with my personal trading every
single day that I trade so now I'm going
to show you an actual example of a trade
that I took with a beautiful Market
pattern and the most effective ones that
you're going to see in the market every
single day so let's start off with the
one that's literally right in front of
our face which is this beautiful
inverted Head and Shoulders the inverted
head and shoulders and also the head and
shoulders are a reversal pattern this is
indicating to us that now the market is
reaching a bottom and then that the
market is going to completely reverse as
you can see right here this is a
beautiful inverted Head and Shoulders
you can see the clear left head and then
the right shoulder and this is where we
entered the trade right at the right
shoulder but if you notice I didn't just
enter the reversal pattern just because
of the reversal pattern I added the
sprinkle on top I I've been mentioning
to you guys with the patterns of Entry
signals which are Morning Star evening
star bullish Eng golfing bearish Eng
golfing which I'm going to review right
now but I did it right here with a
Morning Star formation if you can see
right here this is a three pattern
Candlestick which is known as a Morning
Star formation which is where price
completely stops at a level of support
and then it is completely engulfed by
one Candlestick where it eats the last
two candlesticks it's a three pattern
reversal or continuation pattern which
is exactly what happened here a Morning
Star formation now to give you an
example of what this looks to the
downside it would be something like this
this is a Evening Star bearish engulfing
bearish rejection Candlestick
confirmation this is an evening star cuz
now we're heading to the downside and
this is then a Morning Star cuz now we
are heading to the upside and this is
the trade that I caught here adding the
sprinkle on top with the two Candlestick
dogee rejections how I was just
mentioning to you guys in the last trade
example and and this trade gave me a 1
to 4.5 risk reward so if you would have
risked $11,000 on this trade you would
have made
$4,500 on this trade right here I think
I actually made like 50 $660,000 on this
trade right so with this video you have
a very clear indication on everything
you need to know to read simple price
action and how to use it every single
day and how I've used it for the last
six years and how you can see these very
clear examples of reversal patterns and
price action happening literally in
front of you every single day in the
markets and if you're a beginner Trader
where you're starting from scratch first
of all that's actually crazy because I
didn't come across a price action video
into about a year year and a half into
my journey or if you're even an
experienced Trader and you're struggling
to get results and you want to make
anywhere from a th000 to $1,500 a week
that's where I came up with set and
forget and if you want to know what set
and forget is and what does it even mean
just click the link in the description
below I have a video there that explains
it to Perfection and how Traders all
around the world in the first 3 months
of of trading they're making anywhere
from ,000 to $1,500 a week as a beginner
or even experienced Trader set and
forget has literally gone all around the
world changing Traders lives and if you
want to know more about it and what set
and forget means and how I've turned my
price action strategy into set and
forget just click the link in the
description below I have a video there
for you that explains everything to
Perfection and everything that it
consists of so appreciate you guys
watching this video all the way to the
end and I hope to see you guys in the
next video